Justin Sitarz

1914 E 11th Street • Austin TX, 78702 512 949 9855 • justinsitarz@gmail.com www.justinsitarz.com [personal blog] www.jsfolio.co [portfolio]



Professional Statement

Recent Ruby/Rails bootcamp graduate with experience working in a fast-paced environment and meeting tight deadlines. Created many apps in and out of school utilizing the wealth of possibilities the Rails environment affords – from easy interactions with relational databases and external APIs to integrations with AWS/S3 and other cloud services. Ready and excited to begin working on a team and to start soaking up all the knowledge to truly master all of the tools available for software development.

Experience

Independent Commercial Construction Contractor 2013 - 2014

Collaborated with designers and artists on numerous large design/remodel projects for Austin office spaces Made cost/time estimates for remodeling projects in collaboration with architects and designers Handled construction/remodeling aspects of projects, including electrical, carpentry, plumbing, mechanical

Crew Foreman [The Austin Groundskeeper]

2012 - 2013

Managed crew of 4 – 8 on large commercial and residential landscaping/construction projects Worked with clients, architects, and subcontractors to update and manage build plans throughout projects

Head Arborist [Ladybird Johnson Wildflower Center] 2010 - 2011

Managed Arboretum and garden spaces – maintained plants, trees, and hiking trails

Collaborated with site designers and architects in planning and preparing garden and arboretum additions

Education

Iron Yard Academy [Austin, TX]

2014 - 2015

Worked in an immersive environment to develop and launch multiple Rails projects over the course of 3 months Completed final project in 2 weeks - integrating HTML/CSS design, the Rails stack, and a variety of Ruby gems Ruby/Rails certification

Ex'pression College of Digital Arts [Emeryville, CA]
Bachelor of Applied Science: Audio Engineering - 2007

2004 – 2007

Studied sound engineering and all aspects of recording for music, film, and video games

Skills

- Ruby/Rails proficient
- Javascript/iQuery
- Git/Github user
- Mailer/SMS integration through Twilio/Mandrill
- UNIX CLI experience
- HTML5/CSS/SASS
- AWS/S3/Heroku
- Project management with Trello, etc.